# **Eric Fernando Zuniga**

Seattle, WA

Mobile: (786) 226-7852 Email: ericzuniga24@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/dante940 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericzuniga24

# **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web developer proficient in LAMP, MEAN, and iOS apps written in Swift 2 with an eclectic career as a Mechanical Design Engineer and Process Analyst. Experience in diverse teams has cultivated an appreciation and understanding of multiple disciplines to communicate unique and effective engineering solutions. The ability and desire to effectively acquire new skills reinforces the passion to introduce new experiences to customers in the form of web and mobile applications.

# **EDUCATION**

# Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, 2015

Coding Dojo - Bellevue, WA

Immersive 12 week, full-time web development training program, where nearly 1000 hours of intensive coding experience integrated the implementation and iteration of various projects within the LAMP, MEAN, and iOS Swift development stacks.

# Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, 2010

Florida International University - Miami, FL

# **TECHNICAL TOOLBOX**

Programming Languages	iOS Swift 2, JavaScript, PHP
Frameworks	Express, Angular JS, Codelgniter
Libraries	jQuery, Socket.IO, Twitter Bootstrap
Databases	NoSQL (MongoDB), SQL (MySQL)
Servers	Node.js, Apache
Development Tools	Sublime Text, Git/Github, Terminal
Methodology	MVC, OOP, RESTful, Agile, Scrum
Engineering Skills	CAD (SolidWorks, Inventor), FEA (SolidWorks, Ansys), Six Sigma, Lean
Foreign Languages	Spanish

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python (January 2014)
- ISO 9001:2008 Lead Auditor Certification (October 2011)
- Lean Systems Certification (August 2011)
- Six Sigma: Green Belt Certification (May 2011)
- Professional Certificate in Robotics Engineering (December 2010)

## **PROJECTS**

# **Lighthouse Beacon Service,** September 2015

Designed a web service using MEAN and Node.js where users can set up "beacons" that served as geolocations that other uses could then send their estimated time of arrival to the beacon created/manager. Primarily worked on backend within a team of three. *Tech: MEAN, MongoDB, Node.js, Socket.io.* 

#### Artismo Merchant Website, August 2015

Designed an ecommerce website using PHP and Apache server where users can upload images of pieces of art and sell them through the website. Primarily worked on backend within a team of three. *Tech: PHP, MySQL server, HTML, CSS.* 

# **Tele-operated Search and Rescue Robot**

Florida International University – Undergraduate Research, August 2010 – November 2010 Design of a tele-operated search and rescue robot for the DOE

- Designed parts for prototype in SolidWorks.
- Tested/Sampled various samples of code in C++ and PBASIC.

#### **Compost Accelerator**

Florida International University – Senior Design Project, August 2009 – April 2010

Design of a "green" automated system to accelerate composting and reduce household waste

- Programmed microprocessor to utilize devices to automate various processes.
- Modeled and simulated components in SolidWorks CAD for stress and heat transfer analysis.
- Analyzed data to dramatically increase the rate of vermicomposting within the system.
- Constructed a working prototype using various machining tools.

#### **Advanced Materials Engineering Research Institute**

Florida International University – Undergraduate Research, January 2009 – May 2009

Programmed LabVIEW software procedures to measure field emission from Zinc Oxide nanowires

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Operations Manager, May 2014 - June 2015

Zuniga International Inc. - Miami, FL

- Successfully communicated the needs of clients, foreign and domestic.
- Improved warehouse and inventory workflow to decrease turnaround time of orders.
- Led initiative to implement new technologies such as a more modern inventory system.

# Tooling Engineer, November 2012 - April 2014

HEICO Corporation - Miami, FL

- Designed tools and testing fixtures for aviation repairs and maintenance, in CAD (Autodesk Inventor)
- Implemented workflow process within the production of tools to decrease waste and costs by 90% incurred from duplicate tools.
- Increased satisfaction from aviation mechanics by designing tools with their direct input.
- Redesigned the format of tooling design drawings to improve clarity and reduce errors in machining.

# Junior Consultant, February 2011 – July 2012

Epic Consultants - Miami, FL

- Implemented Six Sigma and ISO:9001 standards for clients.
- Led time studies at retail clients to improve workflow processes.
- Conducted root cause analysis to correct problem areas for clients.
- Led meetings between department leads for the design of a client's webpage and data entry platform.
- Trained clients on the use of a new data entry platform.
- Translated documents from English to Spanish to improve clients' relations with Spanish speaking customers.

# Mechanical Engineering Intern, November 2010 - January 2011

Astronics DME Corporation - Pompano Beach, FL

- Designed and simulated products with Mil-STD for military specifications, in CAD (SolidWorks).
- Produced and tested 3D printed prototypes.
- Tested various working prototypes in photometric and strength labs.
- Represented the engineering team in daily meetings between departments.